Noah Ararat
The Wise Prince, Age 12
Is something bothering you, um...
Her name is Gigi.
Gigi?
Oh, u-um...
The line of people bringing
you birthday gifts
still hasn't ended.
It's been three days...
That's about right.
It lasted a full week last year.
A-A week?!
I can't just receive them
and be done with it.
The item received and its sender
need to be recorded in detail.
It's quite time-consuming.
But I'm sure Evelyn will take
care of everything just fine.
Gigi, you're on the job.
Oh! Right!
Prince Noah, now twelve years old,
has been recognized for fully mastering
the magic sword Leviathan.
By direct imperial order, he is stationed
at the Ministry of Military Affairs,
Ministry of Military Affairs
which presides over the imperial army.
And serving as its minister is...
It's Noah.
Good. Enter.
Henry Ararat
Minister-Prince of Military Affairs, Fourth Prince
There you are, Noah. I've been waiting.
Good morning, Wise Prince.
Yes.
I was told that you wished
to see me, Brother.
Yes.
I wanted to ask your opinion.
We've received an imperial command
to have Reiss here lead a force
to suppress a rebellion
at the southern border.
If those barbarians are shown
any compassion, they get cocky.
So we're to dispatch a regular army
to show them how much
greater our strength is.
I see.
Reiss Keiki, eh?
Reiss Keiki
Direct Subordinate of the Fourth Prince
Aside from his many acts of valor,
he's more than talented
enough to lead an army.
Even among all of my brother's
knights, he is exceptional.
Tell me just one thing.
Of course. Please, ask me anything.
How many soldiers are there, truly?
Born Blessed, So I'll Obtain Ultimate Power
Something wrong?
I asked you how many soldiers
you'll be leading.
Th-That is, um...
What do you mean by "truly," Noah?
Reiss!
What are you hiding?!
P-Please forgive me.
Brother, it's not a serious matter.
But imperial forces receive funding
from the Ministry of Military Affairs
based on how many soldiers
are registered, correct?
Yes.
And it's common for generals
to register non-soldiers,
such as merchants and collaborators,
and keep the excess
funding for themselves.
I sincerely apologize.
Why, you...
Please wait a moment, Brother.
And Reiss, stop cowering.
It's within a general's authority
to add new soldiers.
I'm not trying to place blame.
Normally, that would be fine.
Registering soldiers in name
only can serve as a deterrent.
That's true.
Sometimes it's better to say
you have an army of 100,000, even
if that isn't the actual number.
Precisely.
You understand these matters well.
Brilliant as always, Noah.
But this occasion is different.
The emperor's order was
for a sweeping victory.
That's why I asked about the
extent of your embellishment.
Answer me honestly.
A-Around two thousand, I believe.
Then make sure you can
actually supply that many.
Y-Yes, Your Highness. At once.
May I borrow a pen and paper?
Sure.
Take this to the Ministry
of Military Affairs.
They'll supply enough to cover two
thousand more as miscellaneous expenses.
The excess is yours.
B-But...
Take it. And in return...
I will not tolerate defeat. Understand?
Y-Yes, Your Highness!
Well, well.
What masterful usage of
the carrot and stick.
By the way, Noah...
you haven't experienced
war yet, have you?
Correct.
Even at age twelve,
I'm still at Level 1.
Name: Thirteenth Imperial Prince Noah Ararat
Sex: Male
Title: Wise Prince
Level: 1
/
∞
HP: F+F
Fire: F
MP: F
Water: E+S
Strength: F+E
Wind: F
Stamina: F+F
Earth: F
Intelligence: F+F
Light: F
Spirit: F+F
Dark: F
Speed: F+F
That's the rule of the imperial family.
Many royal babies die prematurely,
meaning they don't survive
long after birth.
Officially, it's attributed
to an epidemic,
but most of them are identified
as murder by poison
by those competing for more power.
Either way, a prince is
a valuable living heir.
They aren't permitted to go to battle
until they've grown to adulthood,
except by imperial order.
You're twelve now.
Wouldn't it look better if
you got some experience now,
before you start ruling your fief?
If the emperor orders me to
go, I'll go at any time.
You have a magic sword. I doubt
you would have much difficulty.
When was your first campaign, Brother?
Oh, me? I—
What's going on?!
Please help me!
Hold up, damn it!
You stupid brats!
You're nothing but trouble!
It's no use trying to run!
Someone, please help!
All right, come with me!
No!
Stop it.
What?
Little brat! Keep your nose
in your own business!
Where's your registration?
Huh?
Your documents?
What is the name of your business?
Answer me.
You know that unregistered slave
trading is a serious crime
under imperial law, right?
Sh-Shut up, you stupid brat!
Get him!
Well done.
Wow...
Incredible!
He handled himself like
a real sword master!
What household does he belong to?
Are you all right?
Y-Yes...
These are underground
slave traders, yes?
They said... we'd be worth good money...
That's enough.
What a pleasure it is to
meet you, Wise Prince.
I make my living off of kids
like the ones you see here.
My name is...
On second thought,
perhaps I shouldn't tell you.
Why not?
Because I work for First Prince Gilbert.
Gilbert Ararat
First Prince
The first prince?
Yes.
Not only does he know who I am,
but he's threatening me not to meddle
because he has Gilbert's backing.
I don't want to make waves here.
Please, just pretend you
never saw any of this.
Brother, do you know this man?
Huh?
No, I don't.
My brother Henry says
he doesn't know you,
nor do I.
But of course not.
A man such as I would not—
I swear...
The nerve of this scoundrel to falsely
claim he serves the first prince.
He may have fooled others, but my
brother and I will not be fooled.
What? So he was a fake?
And... who are those two, anyway?
I know them.
That's the songstress Alichey's patron,
the Wise Prince!
So he's real?
And the others are the fakes?
Apprehend these men and take them
to the first prince's estate.
Explain that they are scoundrels who
falsely claimed to work for Gilbert.
At once.
Bring the children to my mansion for now.
I'll hear their stories later.
Well done, Noah.
You handled that brilliantly.
I'm glad it all worked out.
If they did work for Gilbert,
I couldn't kill them.
But if I'd left them
to their own devices,
the people would think I allowed
underground slave trading to happen.
It's best if I made them out to be fakes,
and let Gilbert handle them himself.
The way you do things always
surprises and amazes me.
Your Highness.
Understood.
What is it, Noah?
A messenger of
First Prince Gilbert was here.
Oh? What did he say?
"Thank you for catching them.
I interrogated the slave traders,
and they were indeed falsely claiming
my name to run their business.
I intended to send them to
court as soon as tomorrow...
but they committed suicide
while my back was turned."
I see.
Honestly...
And people are supposed
to be treasures...
These words must have crossed
my brother's mind as well:
"The lizard has shed its tail."
Gilbert ordered those men to run the
underground slave trade, didn't he?
Yes.
He has absorbed himself in acquiring
shops, buying private estates,
and senseless activities
like that for a long time.
You can't blame him.
Why not?
Fourteenth Prince
Gary
Fourth Prince
Henry
Third Prince
Kilo
Gilbert may be the first prince,
but he's a concubine's son.
Crown Prince, Second Prince
Albert
He can't succeed the throne.
First Prince
Gilbert
Perhaps, to vent his frustration,
he's looking for something he can
do without succeeding the throne.
The slave trade and
private estates are just proxies.
You even know that?
You never cease to amaze me.
Anyone could figure it out
with a bit of thought.
No, not exactly.
This whole thing nauseated me,
but I feel a bit better now.
Episode 6
Dark Clouds
I've pulled some strings.
None of you will ever be sold.
You're all free now.
Is this what I think it is?
Do you have anywhere to go?
No.
I was sold in exchange for money
to buy this year's seed rice.
I was sold to pay for
my mother's funeral.
One less mouth to feed.
My dad really likes to gamble.
As I suspected.
They have no home to return to.
And with parents like that, if they did
go home, they'd just be sold again.
Dylan.
Yes?
I'll take them in.
Find them jobs and places to sleep
wherever available.
And if any wish to study,
help them do it.
Understood. As always, eh?
Y-You're going to buy us?
I'm not buying you.
If you want to leave,
you're free to do so at any time.
But the one thing I won't
tolerate is betrayal.
Is that too difficult for them?
Be grateful for His Highness's
kindness and do the best you can.
Thank him, quickly.
Th-Thank you.
Thank you.
People are treasures, eh?
Oh, that's right!
You called, Master?
All of your birthday gifts have
been handled without incident—
No need to report that.
It is already apparent.
Evelyn, I brought this for you.
What is it?
Your dismissal.
I'd like you to be the administrator
of a small region within Almeria.
Administrator?
Yes. Now you're also a proper
government official.
B-But I...
An administrator is a key office,
also popularly known as a magistrate.
This is a major promotion for a maid.
The fief that the prince received
from the emperor is vast.
It would be impossible for him
to rule over it all himself.
So he has assigned administrators to
various regions to act as his proxies.
I've been watching you for many years,
and you're the most clever of my maids.
I felt that just taking care of guests at
this mansion is a waste of your talents.
B-But... that is... I...
I-I would rather keep working for you
than go out there and
move up in the world!
I know.
But you can, and will, grow.
If you'll work for me as an administrator,
it will be known that I,
the one who appointed you,
am an excellent judge of people.
Evelyn.
Leave this mansion and work for me.
For... you...
A-All right! I understand!
Good.
Amazing.
What is?
It's obvious!
The way you put people to use is
nothing like how the first prince—
Shirley.
That is not something you
should say aloud.
R-Right. I apologize.
But...
he really is amazing.
I've heard the story, Noah.
You managed to defend Gilbert's honor.
It was coincidental.
I merely captured people
who were breaking the law.
So my brother reported it himself.
Smart.
Instead of keeping secrets, he's made
it appear as if his hands are clean.
Still, to think such
scoundrels were out there.
What sort of crime is underground
slave trading, again?
In cases of unregistered slave trading,
the ringleader's dominant
arm is to be severed,
and any others involved are
drafted into military service.
Is that correct, First Prime Minister?
It is precisely as His Highness says.
Oh, right. Were you hurt in any way?
I hear the criminals flew into
a rage and attacked you.
Thankfully, I was able to
turn the tables on them.
I suppose, since it's you,
I didn't even need to ask.
Had it been me,
I would have been undercover,
so I may have been defeated
while debating whether
to reveal my identity.
That would amount to a crime
against the imperial family,
punishable by death.
No.
Under imperial law, if the criminal does
not know His Majesty's identity—
in other words, if he is undercover
and has not yet named himself—
there is no crime against
the imperial family.
It is treated merely as assault.
Did I go too far?
What is or isn't considered rude to say
to the emperor is a delicate matter.
If he was merely being hypothetical,
perhaps I shouldn't have
pointed out his mistake.
It's always best to speak the truth,
but not when it makes a
prime minister look bad.
Should I apologize?
Well, I'd say I won that bet.
Yes. I underestimated him.
Um... what does that mean?
Oh, I just had a little bet going
with the first prime minister.
It was a test to see whether or
not you could describe the law.
O-Oh...
A test? But why?
I have always known that you were strict
and impartial in matters of law.
I was testing that, just to make sure.
Noah...
In the name of the Emperor,
I hereby appoint Noah Ararat
our minister of justice!
Incredible!
Now he's the second minister-prince
after the Fourth Prince!
Long live Noah,
Minister-Prince of Justice! Banzai!
Banzai! Banzai! Banzai! Banzai!
All I did was answer the way I always do,
and I was made minister of justice.
Am I making too much of this?
Or was there something else
behind this decision?
I can see why she's the most popular
songstress in the empire right now.
What a beautiful voice.
I feel like my heart is being cleansed.
True. Maybe it's inelegant to
think about that right now.
It's so good!
Your Majesty, it seems the
report was indeed true.
I see.
I'll let you handle it.
It will be done.
It seems time will wait no longer.
Translation
Timing
Editing
Quality Control
Becky Cottrill
Edgar Cruz
Gabriella Alabanza
S Bilyeu